Tlingit songs and texts collected by Nora Marks Dauenhauer and Richard Dauenhauer
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 1. Tlingit and English recordings, ca. 1950-1997 Bulk: 1970-1990
  - Robert Zuboff, November 7, 1972, Tape 116.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR098)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #26. Side A: 1, Naatsilanéi; 2, Xeet x'eit awoojeilee; 3, Tl'uk' awooswaadee shaawat; 4 Kaats'; 5, Ixt' k'ooxkuyeik (kaxshawdul'ak?); 6 Yikteiyee, mosquito; 7, Lk'ayaak'w - K'ashkeitlk; 8, Man in bentwood box.
  - Robert Zuboff, November 9, 1972, Tape 117.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR099)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #11. 1, X'atlaak; 2, Kuyukwaan; 3, Ch'aak' kugawoosoowoo ts' ootsxan (trans.).
  - Robert Zuboff, November 9, 1972, Tape 118.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR100)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #32. Contents are the same as AFC 2019/004: SR099.
  - Robert Zuboff, August 2, 1973, Tape 119.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR101)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #S-104.
  - Robert Zuboff, August 2, 1973, Tape 120.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR102)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #S-105.
  - Robert Zuboff, August 2, 1973, Tape 121.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR103)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Duplicate of AFC 2019/004: SR101. Kaats' and song. Label reads,"RB copy for Nora." Box and tape have old label #36.
  - Robert Zuboff, August, 1973, Tape 122.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR104)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Kaats and song. Label reads "RD copy for Nora." Box and tape have old label #36.
  - Robert Zuboff, August, 1973, Tape 123.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR105)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Handwriting is Richard Dauenhauer's. Box and tape have old label #38.
  - Robert Zuboff (and Suzie James), August 4, 1973, Tape 124.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR106)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit/English. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and tape have old label #S-102.
  - Robert Zuboff, July 21, 1972, Tape 125.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR107)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: This is the first of a series of three (possibly 4) copies of 7-21-72.
  - Robert Zuboff, July 21, 1972, Tape 126.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR108)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: This is the second of a series of three (possibly 4) copies of 7-21-72. This begins with Raven and the Salmon Box.
  - Robert Zuboff, July 21, 1972, Tape 127.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR109)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: This is the third of a series of three (possibly 4) copies of 7-21-72. This tape begins with Raven creating the Aleutian Islands.
  - Robert Zuboff, July 21, 1972, Tape 128.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR110)
    Speaker's English name: Robert Zuboff. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Shaadaax'. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: unknown. Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan. Father's Clan: Dakl'weidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: This is the fourth of a series of three (possibly 4) copies of 7-21-72. Recording begins with Raven and the Salmon Box, but well into the story, with the octopus Cane Song.
  - George Davis, undated, Tape 129.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR111)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: unknown. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: George Davis interview. Box and tape have old label #57.
  - George Davis, June 20, 1984, Tape 130.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR112)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Raven cyle. Recorded at Sealaska Heritage Foundation, Sealaska Plaza. Old label #7 is on cassete. And "blank" is written on both sides.
  - George Davis, 1980s, Tape 131.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR113)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box insert reads: Tuxstaa or Dleit Kooshdaa; planning for Sitka Native Elders Conference. Nora transcribed Tuxstaa in the 1980s; a draft print out is extant.
  - George Davis, April 1, 1973, Tape 132.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR114)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and cassette are both labeled GD.02, and the following boxes GD.03-05. The box labeled GD.01 in the series does not contain a tape of George Davis, but something unrelated.
  - George Davis, April 2, 1973, Tape 133.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR115)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and cassette are labeled GD.03. Nora Florendo [Dauenhauer] is noted as collector. Side two notes "story No. 6."
  - George Davis, April 2, 1973, Tape 134.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR116)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and cassette are labeled GD.05. Nora Florendo [Dauenhauer] is noted as collector. Side 1 notes "story."
  - George Davis, April 2, 1973, Tape 135.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR117)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Box and cassette are labeled GD.05. Nora Florendo [Dauenhauer] is noted as collector.
  - George Davis, June 20, 1984, Tape 136.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR118)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: George Davis interview, about raven.
  - George Davis, June 20, 1984, Tape 136.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR119)
  - George Davis, June 20, 1984, Tape 136.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR120)
  - George Davis, June 21, 1984, Tape 137.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR121)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: George Davis interview about raven, about the different seasons, about the illnesses that people are getting today, and about Tlingit medicine.
  - George Davis; Austin Hammond, June 22, 1984, Tape 138.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR122)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis; Austin Hammond. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Daanawáak. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven; Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver); Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon); L'ukaax.ádi(Haines). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan; Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Austin Hammond talking with George Davis about they way they lived, the Chinook language, and the first schooner that came to Sitka. George talks about Tlingit land and how decisions concerning the land are do not include Tlingit people. George talks about medicine, and Kooshdaa Kwaáni.
  - George Davis; Austin Hammond, June 22, 1984, Tape 139.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR123)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis; Austin Hammond. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Daanawáak. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven; Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver); Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon); L'ukaax.ádi(Haines). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan; Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Tape 2, recorded by Nora Dauenhauer at Sealaska Heritage Foundation in Juneau. George talks about the growth of salmon, and about Lukaax.ádi land.
  - Austin Hammond, June 22, 1984, Tape 140.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR124)
    Speaker's English name: Austin Hammond. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Daanawáak. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: L'ukaax.ádi (Haines). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: George Davis and Austin Hammond recorded by Nora Dauenhauer at Sealaska Heritage Foundation in Juneau.
  - George Davis, June 24, 1984, Tape 141.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR125)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: George Davis interview.
  - George Davis, June 25, 1984, Tape 142.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR126)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: tape 2. Recorded at Sealaska Heritage Foundation. George Davis discussing the skinning trade, the Angoon battle, whaling at Killisnoow, and the burning of Angoon. Davis talks about At.óow that was sold, and how the Frog house began. He tells about how 10 Aleuts came to fight with Kaagwaantaan. He sings a Beaver song, and explains how the Kaagwaantaan crest is the Beaver, as is the Deishitaan.
  - George Davis, June 25, 1984, Tape 143.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR127)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: tape 3. Recorded at Sealaska Heritage Foundation. George talks about fighting on the reef, Daax haat kanadaa, located by Angoon, and discusses how the peacemakers are made.
  - George Davis, June 26, 1984, Tape 144.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR128)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: tape 1. Recorded at Sealaska Heritage Foundation. George talks about migration from the interior to Haines area, on foot, from Duncan canal. He tells of the flood, and how they were displaced by the glacier. Eva tells of a girl who taught the bird to say Choo-ka-nei-di. George tells of his fishing on the boat Gypsy at Homeshore, as well as stories involving animals. Nora and George discuss sexism in the village and stories involving shamans.
  - George Davis, June 26, 1984, Tape 145.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR129)
    Speaker's English name: George Davis. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kichnáalx; Lk'aanáaw. Speaker's Moiety: Ts'axweil (Crow) *Raven. Speaker's Crest: S'igeidí (Beaver). Speaker's Clan: Deisheetaan (Angoon). Father's Clan: Kaagwaantaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: tape 2. Recorded at Sealaska Heritage Foundation. Conversation about every day things, such as health and work.
  - Jimmie George, May 6, 1973, Tape 146.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR130)
    Speaker's English name: Jimmie George. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Wóochx Kaduhaa. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Kéet (Killer Whale). Speaker's Clan: Dakl'aweidí (Angoon). Father's Clan: Deisheetaan yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Naatsilanéi - Killer Whale story. A story of how one man became a Shaman in Tsaagwáa (a place).
  - Johnny C. Jackson, August 1, 1973, Tape 147.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR131)
    Speaker's English name: Johnny C. Jackson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Gooch Éesh; Naakil.aan. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Kaach.ádi (Kake). Father's Clan: Sit'kweidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Mt. Edgecumbe Hospital, Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Kaach.ádi and Lukaax.ádi separation. Last few minutes of recording is a little messed up.
  - Johnny C. Jackson, August 3, 1973, Tape 148.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR132)
    Speaker's English name: Johnny C. Jackson. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Gooch Éesh; Naakil.aan. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Kaach.ádi (Kake). Father's Clan: Sit'kweidí yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Mt. Edgecumbe Hospital, Sitka, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Continuation of history and story, history of North Pass. He tells of the story of the Hoonah Seagull. He sings Tlingit entrance and exit songs in Tsimpshian.
  - Andrew Johnny, January, 1997, Tape 149.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR133)
    Speaker's English name: Andrew Johnny. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Deitxoon. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Cheech (Porpoise). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Nora Marks Dauenhauer. Description of contents: Sumdum Bay and North Pass. Andrew tells of how they would sleep in their boat in Sumdum Bay and of "real men." He tells of the giant Devil Fish (octopus), the giant rat, and the underwater beetle (or crab?) which was four feet long.
  - J.B. Fawcett; Charlie Joseph, 1968, Tape 150.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR134)
    Speaker's English name: J.B. Fawcett; Charlie Joseph. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tseexwáa; Kaal.átk'. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle); Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Toos' (Shark); Gooch (Wolf). Speaker's Clan: Wooshkeetaan (Hoonah); unknown. Father's Clan: T'akdeintaa; unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Katherine Mills. Description of contents: first recorded onto open reel tape (1968), and then transferred to cassette on 2/25/1999. Shark House Potlatch in Hoonah, Alaska.
  - Jessie Dalton, 1968, Tape 151.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR135)
    Speaker's English name: Jessie Dalton. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Daax'wudaak; Naa Tláa. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Kittiwake. Speaker's Clan: T'akdeintaan. Father's Clan: Wooshkeetaan. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Hoonah, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: first recorded onto open reel tape (1968), and then transferred to cassette. Continuation of SR134. Shark House Potlatch in Hoonah, Alaska.
  - Unidentified, undated, Tape 152.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR136)
    Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Interior songs.
  - Unidentified, undated, Tape 153.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR137)
    Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: mourning songs. Memorial songs for Alfred Andrews hosted by James Klanott.
  - Jim Marks, 1950s, Tape 154.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR138)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kuháanx'; Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Marks original songs.
  - Jack David, 1950s, Tape 155.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR139)
    Speaker's English name: Jack David. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Tsagwált. Speaker's Moiety: Yéil (Raven). Speaker's Crest: Gaat (Sockeye). Speaker's Clan: Lukaax.ádi (Duncan Canal). Father's Clan: unknown. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Eagle Spirit. Jack David and Jim Marks telling stories, including one about a giant octopus (Devil Fish).
  - Jack David, 1950s, Tape 155.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR140)
  - Jim Marks, 1950s, Tape 156.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR141)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kuháanx'; Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Personal songs. Willie Marks is singing also.
  - Jim Marks, 1950s, Tape 157.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR142)
    Speaker's English name: Jim Marks. Speaker's Tlingit Name: Kuháanx'; Goox Guwakaan. Speaker's Moiety: Ch'áak' (Eagle). Speaker's Crest: Xóots (Brown Bear). Speaker's Clan: Chookaneidí (Hoonah). Father's Clan: Lukaax.ádi yádi. Language: Tlingit. Location recorded: Juneau, Alaska. Recorded by: Horace Marks and/or Johnny Marks. Description of contents: Lukaax.ádi story. Date of 12/30/1971 is written on cassette label.
  - Jack David, 1950s, Tape 158.; 1 sound cassette: analog (Item-id AFC 2019/004: SR143)